<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Sajjad Momeni</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Sajjad Momeni</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Sajjad Momeni, a Machine Learning Engineer and AI enthusiast. I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about developing intelligent systems and solving complex problems using artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I specialize in:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Deep Learning&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Natural Language Processing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Computer Vision&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Through this blog, I share my experiences, insights, and knowledge about AI and Machine Learning. Feel free to connect with me through the social links or email if you&amp;rsquo;d like to discuss AI, collaborate on projects, or just have a chat about technology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepSeek: A Deep Dive into the Next Generation Language Model</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/research/what-is-deepseek/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/research/what-is-deepseek/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Transformer from Scratch: My Journey into the Heart of Modern AI</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/research/my-transformers-journy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/research/my-transformers-journy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Introduction&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#introduction&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I first encountered transformer models like GPT and BERT, they seemed like magical black boxes. The capabilities were impressive, but I wanted to understand what was happening under the hood. So I embarked on a journey to build a transformer from scratch, component by component.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share what I learned, the challenges I faced, and the code I wrote to implement a GPT-style transformer model in PyTorch. By the end, I hope you&amp;rsquo;ll have a deeper understanding of how these powerful models work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcement Learning Process and Its Application in Complex Problems</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/research/lunar-lander/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/research/lunar-lander/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reinforcement Learning (RL) is a significant branch of machine learning where an agent interacts with an environment and improves its behavior based on the rewards it receives. In this article, we will explore the reinforcement learning process, answer some of your questions, and provide a complete example with Python code, including explanations of arrays, matrices, and the model training process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;1-introduction-to-reinforcement-learning&#34;&gt;&#xA;  1. Introduction to Reinforcement Learning&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#1-introduction-to-reinforcement-learning&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In reinforcement learning, an agent is placed in an environment and takes various actions to change its state. After each action, the agent receives a reward. The ultimate goal is to learn an optimal policy that selects actions in each state to maximize long-term rewards.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>روز اول سفر به قشم – ماجراهای قطار و اولین آشنایی‌ها</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/other/qeshm-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/other/qeshm-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;روز-اول-سفر-به-قشم--ماجراهای-قطار-و-اولین-آشناییها&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;strong&gt;روز اول سفر به قشم – ماجراهای قطار و اولین آشنایی‌ها&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#%d8%b1%d9%88%d8%b2-%d8%a7%d9%88%d9%84-%d8%b3%d9%81%d8%b1-%d8%a8%d9%87-%d9%82%d8%b4%d9%85--%d9%85%d8%a7%d8%ac%d8%b1%d8%a7%d9%87%d8%a7%db%8c-%d9%82%d8%b7%d8%a7%d8%b1-%d9%88-%d8%a7%d9%88%d9%84%db%8c%d9%86-%d8%a2%d8%b4%d9%86%d8%a7%db%8c%db%8c%d9%87%d8%a7&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;همه چیز از صبح روز اول شروع شد. مهدی و محمدرضا اومدن دنبالم و منم تند تند وسایلم رو جمع کردم. مامانم برامون یه کم بندری آماده کرده بود، داغ داغ برش داشتم و دویدم دم در. چمدون‌ها رو بار زدیم و راه افتادیم به سمت ایستگاه قطار اصفهان. بعد از گذاشتن وسایل توی دستگاه ایکس‌ری، رفتیم سمت قطار.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
